# **DONNIE HICKS**

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER\***

## **Summary**

I completed a History degree with highest honours before working in communications and sales for the second largest telecom company in the world. After relocating to Canada I continued as a professional communicator at the City of Toronto for nearly a decade as an Advanced Emergency Medical Dispatcher. Wishing to grow outside of that role and inspired by the potential of working with software professionally, I transformed my hobby in computers into a career as a Full Stack Developer.

## Goal

I am seeking a positive work environment that appreciates my broad skill set and diverse experience, and gives me an opportunity to work with Javascript, React and GraphQL. I am particularly interested in writing code in the Functional Programming paradigm, and generating blazing-fast, static, low-maintenance, and secure web applications with the JAM Stack and Serverless architecture.

## **Employment**

# Hyxos Toronto

## Cofounder/Full Stack Developer

March 2013 to Current

In 2013 I cofounded Hyxos Inc. with my partner in order to pursue business projects. In our most recent endeavour I designed and produced the first edition of a card game called TZI using Python to programmatically generate image assets. I created our product website with Javascript and GatsbyJS, building it with React components and querying content data through Gatsby's GraphQL API.

# The Brewbox Company Full Stack Developer

Toronto

Sept. 2016 to March 2017

I organized and automated the process of synchronizing customer data with Mailchimp through their API for email marketing purposes. I worked with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL and Javascript to maintain and extend administrative and other backend support features of the company web portal.

# The City of Toronto

**Toronto** 

# Advanced Emergency Medical Dispatcher

Sept. 2006 to Oct. 2015

Following established medical protocols, I determined the prioritization of incoming 911 calls and administered first-aid and CPR instructions over the phone. Through radio and telephone channels I dispatched ambulances crews and strategically managed departmental resources to ensure paramedic safety and produce optimal patient outcomes.

# AT&T (formerly SBC) Billing Specialist

Tulsa, Oklahoma

Sept. 2002 to May 2003

Fielding inbound calls regarding billing questions, I explained policies, billing procedures, and presented product offerings as solutions to customer needs based on personalized profiles.

# **Projects**

#### www.tzi.cards

February 2019 to Current

A card game inspired by the lunar calendar. TZI Cards reimagines traditional playing cards and explores the ancient Chinese system of Heavenly Stems and Earthly branches. I built the product home page using the Gatsby static site generator library, and deployed it through Netlify. I also designed and produced all of the digital art assets for the product and site.

#### 1hx.ca

October 2009 to Current

A short-link generator based on YOURLS. I have used open source software to keep this personal project alive and running on the internet for almost ten years. Originally served on a shared hosting platform, I have migrated it through different backend configurations multiple times. Currently running on Ubuntu in a VPS, routing through Nginx, SSL through letsencrypt, and data storage with MySQL.

#### Contact

donnie@hyxos.ca

416-878-4790

**♥** Toronto, Ontario, Canada

in donniehicks

**y** macbraughton

hyxos

### **Skills**

#### **Frontend**

HTML CSS/SCSS/SASS Markup

#### **Programming Languages**

Javascript Python Ruby

#### Libraries

Gatsby React GraphQL

#### **Frameworks**

Rails Django

#### **Backend**

Linux/Unix
PostgreSQL/MySQL/SQLite
Nodejs
MongoDB
SSL/TLS

#### Education

### Oral Roberts University

Sept. 1997 to May 2001

BA in History 2001

3.97 GPA Summa Cum Laude Academic Peer Adviser Minors: Philosophy, Modern Hebrew

**Lighthouse** Oct. to Dec. **Labs** 2015

Web Development Bootcamp

Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL Javascript

Advanced
Analytics and
Research Lab

Jan. 2018

Citizen Data Scientist L- III

Introduction to Data Science R Programming Language

### **Hobbies**

Playing Guitar and Drums Singing and Songwriting Playing Video and Board Games Bee-Keeping